Guide to the Brooklyn Fire Department publications 1985.087
Brooklyn Historical Society
Brooklyn Fire Department publications
1831-1873
Brooklyn Historical Society
Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.). Fire Department
1985.087
0.5 Linear Feet in one manuscipt box.
The Brooklyn Fire Department publications includes the constitution and bylaws of the Village of Brooklyn Fire Department and reports, acts, prospectuses, and codes related to the Brooklyn Fire Department and its various iterations in the late 19th century.
Conditions Governing Access
Open to users without restriction.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Source and date of acquisition unknown. The collection was formally accessioned in 1985.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into three series by type. Within each series, materials are arranged chronologically.
Related Materials
James A. Kelly collection of Brooklyn firefighting records (1989.006)
Brooklyn Fire Department pamphlets (1985.070)
Brooklyn Fire Department payroll records (1985.077)
Board of Trustees of the Brooklyn Fire Department meeting minutes (1977.080)
Brooklyn Fire Department ledgers (1990.004)
Brooklyn Fire Department journals (1985.024)
Brooklyn Fire Department discharge (1992.018)
Village of Brooklyn Fire Department member lists and minutes (1973.275)
Williamsburgh fire wardens minute book (1977.158)
Scope and Contents
The Brooklyn Fire Department publications include several items related to the Brooklyn Fire Department, including the constitution and bylaws of the Village of Brooklyn Fire Department, reports and acts concerning the reorganization of the City of Brooklyn Fire Department, reports of the chief engineers of the Eastern and Western Districts, reports of the Fire Marshalls, a prospectus for the Brooklyn Fire Extinguishing Company, and a copy of the fire and buildings inspection code.
Prospectuses; Fire fighters -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Fire prevention -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Constitutions; Bylaws (administrative records); Reports; Annual reports; Legislative acts; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.). Fire Department
- Series 1: Constitutions and by-laws
  - Village of Brooklyn Fire Department constitution and by-laws, 1831 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - By-Laws, Rules and Regulations of the Brooklyn Fire Department, 1856 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Fire Department of the Eastern District, City of Brooklyn by-laws, 1861, 1867 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Series 2: Acts, ordinances and laws
  - An Act to Establish Fire Limits in the City of Brooklyn, 1852, 1855 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - An Ordinance to Establish a Fire Department in the City of Brooklyn, 1858 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - The Fire Limits of the City of Brooklyn, 1861, 1865, 1868 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - An Act to Re-Organize the Fire Department of the City of Brooklyn, 1869 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Fire and Buildings Law, 1873 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Series 3: Reports and prospectuses
  - Fire Marshal's Semi-Annual Report, 1854-1861 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Report of the Chief Engineer of the Fire Department of the Eastern District of Brooklyn, 1856-1858, 1862 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Brooklyn Fire Department Fund annual report, 1858-1859 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Report of the Special Committee in the Matter of Reorganizing the Fire Department of the City of Brooklyn, 1858, 1861 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Annual report of the Chief Engineer of the Fire Department, Brooklyn, Western District, 1859-1862, 1866 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Report of the Fire Marshal of Brooklyn, Eastern District to the Underwriters of Brooklyn and New York, 1863-1864 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Fire Marshal's Report to the Mayor…of the City of Brooklyn, 1866 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Prospectus of the Brooklyn Fire Extinguishing Company, 1870 (Box 1, Folder 3)